♪ In the face of turbulence ♪
♪ 面对动荡 ♪
♪ Your roots are firm ♪
♪ 你的根很牢固 ♪
♪ To this piece of land ♪
♪ 来到这片土地 ♪
♪ Chasing the flow of the waves ♪
♪ 追逐海浪的流动 ♪
♪ The fallen leaves ♪
♪ 落叶 ♪
♪ The horizon ♪
♪ 地平线 ♪
♪ Split Away ♪
♪ 分开 ♪
♪ At the end of the world ♪
♪ 在世界的尽头 ♪
♪ It's forever ♪
♪ 永远都是这样 ♪
♪ When we met and parted ♪
♪ 当我们相遇又分离 ♪
♪ When we depend on each other ♪ ♪ and we move away ♪
♪ 当我们互相依赖时 ♪ ♪ 然后我们就离开了 ♪
♪ I never forgot ♪
♪ 我从未忘记 ♪
♪ I cross the edge of the sword ♪
♪ 我跨过剑锋 ♪
♪ Crossing the starry sky ♪
♪ 穿越星空 ♪
♪ Falling dreams ♪
♪ 坠落的梦想 ♪
♪ Walk with me to tell the story of the wind ♪
♪ 与我同行，讲述风的故事 ♪
♪ The wind blows its waves ♪
♪ 风吹起波浪 ♪
♪ I see the thousands of candles cross ♪
♪ 我看到成千上万的蜡烛交叉 ♪
♪ The vast land and the boundless sea ♪
♪ 辽阔的土地和无边的海洋 ♪
♪ Red clothes flying high ♪
♪ 红衣飞得很高 ♪
♪ In the face of bitterness, sadness ♪ ♪ Emotion and happy adventure ♪
♪ 面对苦涩、悲伤 ♪ ♪ 情感和快乐的冒险 ♪
♪ I just hope you're by my side ♪
♪ 我只希望你在我身边 ♪
♪ I just want you to be by my side ♪
♪ 我只想你在我身边 ♪
♪ Like an interconnected tower ♪ ♪ I will accompany you until the end ♪
♪ 就像一座相连的塔 ♪ ♪ 我会陪你直到最后 ♪
♪ Seeing the fireflies that fill our shoulders ♪ ♪ On our shoulders ♪
♪ 看到萤火虫充满我们的肩膀 ♪ ♪ 在我们的肩膀上 ♪
♪ I don't regret it, I have no doubts ♪
♪ 我不后悔，我毫不怀疑 ♪
= Wonderland of Love =
= 爱的仙境 =
= Episode 20 =
= 第 20 集 =
Do you think that
你认为
Can you make Mr. Qin change his mind?
你能让秦先生回心转意吗？
Mr Qin,
Mr Qin,
despite being strong, he has a soft heart.
尽管他很坚强，但 他却有一颗柔软的心。
Others look at him as on countless battlefields,
别人看着他就像 在无数的战场上，
on countless battlefields.
在无数的战场上。
In fact, he is very kind,
其实他很善良，
and nice.
很好。
With the right words,
用正确的话语，
I'm sure I can change his mind.
我确信我可以改变他的想法。
His Majesty ordered Lord Qin to reflect on his mistakes.
陛下命秦王 反省自己的错误。
The master said that many people a letter of complaint
师傅说很多人都有 投诉信
from Mr. Qin, right?
是秦先生送来的吧？
When the tree is tall and strong, the wind will blow it.
树高大粗时， 风就会吹它。
Lord Qin
秦王
did a great feat this time.
这次做了一件伟大的事。
So others are jealous of him.
所以别人都嫉妒他。
Now His Majesty is angry.
现在陛下生气了。
If Lord Qin refuses to bow to him,
如果秦王不肯向他跪拜，
I fear they among them.
我害怕他们 中间的他们。
And this will greatly affect Lord Qin's future.
而这将会极大地影响 秦王的未来。
Greetings, Lord Qin.
秦王您好。
Srta. GU,
斯尔塔。顾，
I should have visited Prime Minister Gu in person.
我应该 亲自拜访顾总理。
But I can't just leave the house.
但我不能就这样 离开家。
When you return,
你什么时候回来，
apologize for me.
为我道歉。
He's very polite.
他很有礼貌。
Actually, I didn't come today
其实我今天没来
to defend my father.
保卫我的父亲。
Today I came of my own free will.
今天我是自愿来的。
I have something
我有一些东西
to give you.
为你带来。
Miss. GU is very friendly.
顾小姐非常友善。
I have everything I need.
我有我需要的一切。
How can I accept a gift from you?
我怎样才能接受你的礼物？
This was embroidered by me.
这是我绣的。
When I was in the capital, with my old friends.
当我在首都的时候， 和我的老朋友们在一起。
Fortunately, some people
幸运的是，有些人
they saw their biological mother.
他们看到了自己的亲生母亲。
So I embroidered
于是我就绣了
I made this portrait of Mrs. Liu
我为刘女士画了这幅肖像
According to the description.
根据描述。
After finishing,
完成后，
I showed everyone that
我向大家展示了
who knew Ms. Liu.
谁认识刘女士。
I heard this portrait is just like her.
听说这幅画 很像她。
Lord Qin.
秦王爷。
Miss. GU took too long
顾小姐时间太长了
to look for people
寻找人
who have seen Ms. Liu.
谁见过刘女士。
She also asked them to
她还要求他们
to describe Ms. Liu to her.
向她描述一下刘女士。
So she made a sketch
于是她画了一张草图
and worked on this portrait
并创作了这幅肖像
until your eyes were red
直到你的眼睛红了
until his eyes were red.
直到他的眼睛都红了。
Finally managed to finish this portrait on time.
终于 按时完成了这幅肖像画。
Your Highness.
殿下。
It's really sad
真的很难过
not grow
不成长
grow up under the care of a mother.
在母亲的呵护下长大。
But Madam Liu
但刘女士
you will find it very good
你会发现它非常好
you are so brave and capable.
你是如此勇敢和有能力。
Thank you, Miss. GU.
谢谢顾小姐。
So I will accept
所以我会接受
this painting.
这幅画。
You are an intelligent and understanding person.
你是一个聪明 、善解人意的人。
You must know that
你必须知道
Ms. Liu wouldn't like it
刘女士不喜欢
because of his title,
因为他的头衔，
because of her.
因为她。
Look, Your Highness.
瞧，殿下。
I bordei is retrato
我 bordei 是 retrato
to embroider this painting.
来绣这幅画。
If you want to hang her painting
如果你想挂她的画
to be used for memorial purposes,
用于纪念目的，
the color will not fade
颜色不会褪色
it won't disappear it won't disappear.
它不会消失 它不会消失。
Miss. GU is so attentive.
顾小姐真细心。
Thank you very much.
非常感谢。
The princess is very nice
公主非常好
I know that
我知道
You can't have a guest here for long.
你不能在这里 长期接待客人。
I'm leaving.
我走了。
Miss,
错过，
Don't you want to convince Mr. Qin
难道你不想 说服秦先生吗？
to apologize to Her Majesty.
向太后陛下道歉。
Why don't you say anything?
你为什么不说话？
And he left in a hurry.
然后他就匆匆离开了。
I messed up.
我搞砸了。
Mister Qin takes the title
秦先生夺冠
It is serious.
这很严重。
Right now, seeing his expression,
此刻，看到他的表情，
if I change his mind,
如果我改变他的主意
he would be unhappy.
他会不高兴的。
And also,
并且，
the portrait of Lady Liu.
刘夫人画像。
And every time he portrays it,
而每次他 描绘它的时候，
he will thank me.
他会感谢我的。
Since I got what I wanted,
自从我得到了我想要的，
I can't be better than him.
我不可能比他更好。
Will he really give up
他真的会放弃吗
of Lord Qin's position?
秦王的地位如何？
Will the king punish him again?
国王会再次惩罚他吗？
He is the chosen king.
他是被选中的国王。
Everything will go well for him.
对他来说一切都会顺利。
For someone like Lord Qin,
对于秦王这样的人来说，
others
其他的
Maybe they can beat him in this fight,
也许他们能在这场战斗中击败他
but they can't win the game.
但他们无法赢得 比赛。
You are back.
你回来了。
I went back.
我回去了。
Do not look at me.
别看着我。
She did not respond to his letter.
她没有回复他的信。
She didn't even open her letter.
她甚至没有打开信。
I won't wait for her answer.
我不会等待她的答复。
But to be honest,
但说实话，
what did Miss Cui say
崔小姐说什么
you're right.
你说得对。
She said that in the current situation,
她表示，在目前的情况下，
you should think we are at war.
你应该认为我们正处于战争状态。
When will you attack?
你什么时候进攻？
And when
什么时候
stop and regroup?
停下来重新集结？
In truth,
事实上，
you know what to do.
你知道该做什么。
What is that?
那是什么？
It's my mother's portrait.
这是我母亲的肖像。
They say this portrait is just like her.
他们说这幅肖像 就像她一样。
I've never seen her before.
我以前从未见过她。
This painting
这幅画
It is well embroidered.
它绣得很好。
It almost looks real.
它看起来几乎是真的。
Sim.
西姆。
Miss. GU sent.
顾小姐发来的。
She said for a long time.
她说 了好久。
It's from Miss. GU?
是顾小姐寄来的？
It seems that Miss GU
看来顾小姐
cares a lot about you.
很关心你。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
Is she interested in you?
她对你感兴趣吗？
She and I
她和我
we are totally different people.
我们是完全不同的人。
Beauty is in the eye of the beholder.
美在旁观者的眼中。
Eu
欧洲联盟
at Miss Cui.
还有崔小姐。
Miss Cui
崔小姐
Haven't read your letter yet.
还没读你的信。
Is the governor of Biandu better?
边都都督比较好吗？
The doctor said acupuncture was used
医生说用针灸
it is neutralizing the poison. A secret medicine.
它正在中和毒素。 一种秘药。
He said the poison has already been neutralized .
他说毒已经被中和了 。
This poison
这毒
For a long time.
许久。
Governor.
州长。
(Qingyun Temple) At that time, I promised Lord Qin
（青云寺） 当时我就答应了秦大人
if he swore to protect the imperial great-grandson
如果他发誓要保护 皇曾孙
and put him on the throne,
并把他推上王位，
I would find a way to poison Sun Jing.
我会想办法 毒死孙靖。
I was also prepared
我也做好了准备
to die with him.
和他一起死。
But I never thought that
但我从没想过
that would fail.
那会失败的。
And he still fled to Tong Pass.
而他还是逃到了潼关。
I couldn't keep my promise.
我没能遵守 诺言。
Duque.
杜克。
You did your best.
你已经尽力了。
It was all in the hands of the gods.
这一切都掌握在众神的手中。
Lord Qin sent me a letter yesterday.
秦大人昨天给我写了一封信。
He wrote that although Sun Jing was defeated now,
他写道，孙敬虽 败，
the threat remained unbreakable.
这种威胁仍然牢不可破。
We still have to be cautious.
我们还是要保持谨慎。
Write a letter to General Han
给韩将军写信
for him to keep keep hidden
让他保持 隐藏
for now.
目前。
Sim.
西姆。
Your Highness.
殿下。
We have a letter from Consort Xiao.
我们收到了萧妃的来信。
How is my mother?
我妈妈怎么样了？
Lord Qin claimed Xichang
Lord Qin claimed Xichang
but I didn't receive my mother.
但我没有接待 我的母亲。
I was worried
我很担心
something had happened to her.
她出了什么事。
Don't worry,
不用担心，
Concubine Xiao is alive and well.
萧妃还健在。
She has
她有
No Templo Qingyun
No Templo Qingyun
no Templo Qingyun.
no Templo Qingyun.
Since the capital Biandu has been restored,
自复都汴都以来 ，
Can we go back to the city?
我们可以回城吗？
Your Highness.
殿下。
Consort Xiao sent us a letter
萧妃给我们来信
to make us bear this for a while longer.
让我们再忍受 一段时间。
What can we trust
我们可以相信什么
we can trust
我们可以信任
with Lord Qin in the capital.
与秦王在京城。
But Lord Xin and Lord Qi
但辛君和齐君
have great ambitions.
有远大的抱负。
A concubina Xiao
A concubina Xiao
asked us to hide.
要求我们 躲起来。
I fear there are still many
恐怕还有很多
who want to hurt you.
谁想伤害你。
I know.
我知道。
Does Lord Xin want to lead the Zhenxi army to Changzhou?
辛大人难道要率镇西军攻打 常州吗？
Sim.
西姆。
During today's court meeting,
在今天的法庭会议上，
my father asked me to
我父亲要求我
to lead our army to Changzhou
率军进驻常州
to stop Sun Jing from summoning to stop Sun Jing from summoning.
阻止孙靖召唤 阻止孙靖召唤。
And Lord Xin volunteered to lead the army.
辛君自告奋勇 领军。
And the pedantic ministers said that since the founding of this country,
而那些迂腐的大臣们却说， 自从这个国家成立以来，
Since the founding of this country, it has always been in the hands of you.
这个国家自建国以来， 始终掌握在你们手中。
Therefore, they agreed that
因此，他们一致认为
It is better to let Lord Xin lead the army.
还不如 让辛主领军呢。
How ridiculous.
多么可笑啊。
Have they forgotten how he lost Luoyang?
难道他们忘记了他是怎么失去洛阳的吗？
If he leads the army,
如果他率领军队，
It's like sending the Zhenxi army on a suicide mission.
这就像派镇西军 去执行自杀任务一样。
Furthermore,
此外，
he involved Lord Qi in this.
他把齐王也牵扯进来了。
He said Mr. Qi can help you
他说齐先生可以帮你
to help him.
来帮助他。
No final,
没有最终，
they almost succeeded in persuading the emperor
他们几乎成功 说服了皇帝
Has the emperor already ordered?
皇上已经下令了吗？
And still not
但仍然没有
to the Palace Secretariat.
到宫中书院。
But the position of the emperor
但皇帝的地位
the position of the king.
国王的地位。
He will appoint Lord Qin as the Commander-in-Chief,
他将任命秦王 为统帅，
Lord Qi as general
齐王为将军
and me as vanguard.
而我作为先锋。
All three soldiers
三个士兵都
go to Changzhou
去常州
Lord Xin is trying to kill two birds with one stone
辛王欲 一石二鸟
He wants to stay in Changzhou to wait until his opponent wears out.
他想留在常州， 等待对手疲惫不堪。
If he can
如果他可以的话
the Jing troops that were sent to Baiyue,
派往百越的荆军，
he can achieve a great feat.
他可以取得伟大的成就。
Second,
第二，
he wants to seize the military power of the Zhenxi army.
他要夺取镇西军的兵权。
My father also said that.
我父亲也这么说过。
My father also said that
我父亲也说过
that Lord Xin is always looking is already looking
辛王一直在寻找， 已经在寻找
It's been a while.
有一阵子了。
But he hasn't achieved anything yet.
但他还没有取得任何成就。
In terms of reputation,
就声誉而言，
he cannot be compared to you.
他无法与你相比。
That's why he's looking forward to
这就是为什么他期待
he wants to reach Changzhou.
他要去常州。
As tropes de Sun Jing para Baiyue
As tropes de Sun Jing para Baiyue
It is made up of battle-experienced veterans.
它由具有丰富战斗经验的退伍军人组成。
Although they are tired,
虽然他们很累，
but it doesn't mean being easily defeated.
但这并不意味着 容易被击败。
Lord Xin is arrogant and frantic, he doesn't know how to lead troops.
辛君狂妄狂妄， 不懂得带兵。
O Sr. Qi
奥先生。齐
He's a little smart, but he doesn't have enough courage.
他有一点聪明， 但没有足够的勇气。
They can't fight together,
他们不能并肩作战
win a battle together,
一起打胜仗，
their incompetence
他们的无能
it will only lead the army to death.
只会导致军队死亡。
Maybe.
或许。
Come, bite.
来来来，咬一口。
Bite, bite. - My God.
咬，咬。 - 我的上帝。
Majesty.
威严。
What it was?
这是什么？
Skirt.
裙子。
Your Majesty.
陛下。
Mister Qin wrote you a letter.
秦先生给你写了一封信。
Please take a look
请看一下
I let him reflect on his crimes, right?
我让他反省 自己的罪行吧？
He knows
他知道
what did he do wrong?
他做错了什么？
Why are you writing me a letter?
你为什么给我写信？
I won't read it.
我不会读它。
Take him away.
把他带走。
Pai,
拜县，
Why don't you read it?
你为什么不读一下呢？
See Li Ni
就是这样
ask for absurd things,
要求荒谬的事情，
you can reject it.
你可以拒绝它。
(Letter to the Emperor)
（给皇帝的信）
I've been thinking about it all day.
我一整天都在想这件事。
Plus, I can't sleep well.
另外，我睡不好觉 。
I fought with you
我与你并肩作战
By my mother's title.
以我母亲的名义。
She has already passed away
她已经去世了
and as your son,
作为你的儿子，
while she was alive, while she was alive.
趁她还活着， 趁她还活着。
Now I'm sad that ♪ She passed away.
现在我很伤心 ♪ 她去世了。
She will live forever in my heart.
她将永远活在我心里。
The other ministers feel sorry for me
其他部长都为我感到难过
and considered my statement
并考虑了我的陈述
as an act of filial love.
作为一种孝顺之爱的行为。
But the etiquette ritual
但礼仪仪式
It's to give to my mother for my mother.
是 替妈妈送给妈妈的。
I dare not disagree.
我不敢苟同。
I will respect what you took.
我会尊重 你拿走的东西。
I will respect.
我会尊重。
I have already sent a letter to the emperor
我已经给皇上写信了
to give to my mother to calm the argument
送给我妈妈 以平息争吵
to calm the discussion.
以平息讨论。
I believe the emperor the imperial decree
我相信皇帝的 圣旨
within the next few years.
未来几年内。
Your Highness,
殿下，
when you come back,
当你回来时，
Please, ask
请问
Prime Minister Gu
顾总理
to deliver the Ministry of Rites to the tomb
送礼部 至墓
to deal with of the late empress.
对付 已故的皇后。
You are...
你是...
This wedding ceremony
这场婚礼
can lead this ceremony.
可以主持这个仪式。
Lord Xin won't want
辛爷不会要
the prince.
王子。
To speak the truth,
说实话，
I don't want to leave Lord Xin and Lord Qi
我不想离开辛王爷和齐王爷
lead the army to Changzhou.
率军进驻常州。
Understood.
明白了。
I will pass your message
我会转达你的讯息
for my father.
为了我的父亲。
Pai,
拜县，
what Li Ni wrote
李妮写的
in your letter?
在你的信中？
He said he did n't want to harm me.
他说他不想 伤害我。
So he asked me
于是他问我
to give to the mother to check on the mother.
送给母亲，让 母亲检查一下。
At first, he would rather give up Lord Qin's throne
当初他宁愿放弃 秦王的皇位
because of his mother's title.
因为他母亲的头衔。
And he embarrassed the Lady during the court meeting.
他在法庭会议上让女士难堪了。
Why did he write an apology letter
他为什么要写一封道歉信
write you an apology letter?
给你写一封道歉信？
That's why,
这就是为什么，
to warn others, to warn others.
警告别人， 警告别人。
Look.
看。
By asking him, to reflect on his mistakes.
通过询问他， 反思自己的错误。
Li Ni may have been left with
李妮可能已被留下
You may be sorry.
你可能会后悔。
But maybe
但也许
He still has a grudge against you.
他对你还是有怨恨的。
As he has already admitted his mistakes,
既然他已经承认了 自己的错误，
I think it's better to check
我认为 最好检查一下
to Mother.
给母亲。
After all, you and Lai's mother
毕竟你和赖妈妈
They are the Empress.
他们是皇后。
The ministers were also right.
大臣们也是对的。
I only have three children.
我只有三个孩子。
Just his mother
只是他的母亲
received the title of a goddess.
获得了女神的称号。
It's really not appropriate.
确实不太合适。
He already wrote this letter of apology
他已经写了这封道歉信
right now,
现在，
only for
仅适用于
lead the army to Changzhou.
率军进驻常州。
If, as soon as he admits his mistakes,
如果他一旦承认错误
if you let him lead the army
如果你让他率领军队
he will become even more arrogant.
他会变得更加傲慢。
If you do,
如果你这样做，
he will not be afraid or respect you.
他不会害怕 或尊重你。
Don't worry,
不用担心，
since it is effective to reflect on your mistakes,
因为反思自己的错误是有效的，
I will leave it
我会留下它
for a while longer.
再持续一段时间。
Mr He,
何先生，
Mr Qin was arrested
秦先生被捕
long time.
很久。
Why are you going
你为什么走
Did you just come see him now?
你现在才来看他吗？
He wrote a letter to the emperor
他给皇帝写了一封信
to give to the emperor for his mother.
为他的母亲献给皇帝 。
But since the Ministry of Etiquette received the imperial decree,
但自从礼部 接到圣旨后，
her mother was eventually named as a worthy concubine.
她的母亲最终被封为 贤妃。
Now it's decided.
现在决定了。
Mister Qin relented.
秦先生心软了。
This subject
这个主题
this subject?
这个主题？
It can resolve a dispute.
它可以解决争端。
But as soon as a heart gets hurt,
但心一旦受伤，
cannot be cured easily.
不能轻易治愈。
I have to go see him.
我得去见他。
(Lord Qin's Residence)
（秦王府）
Mr He,
何先生，
It's not easy for us to enter like this.
我们能这样进入也不容易。
But Mister Qin's mansion is huge.
不过秦先生的府邸很大。
Where did he go?
他去哪了？
You have the whistle, right?
你有口哨，对吧？
Hurry up and ask Ear to guide us.
赶紧请耳朵来指导我们吧。
You are sure,
你确定，
taozi, Tenente He.
taozi, Tenente He.
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
Take this girl
带上这个女孩
to find Mr. Qin.
去找秦先生。
Okay, let's go.
好吧，我们走吧。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
Bring me more drink.
给我多拿点饮料来。
Bring me more drink!
再给我拿点饮料来！
It can leave.
它可以离开。
You don't have to serve me.
你不必为我服务。
Don't you really want me to serve you wine?
你真的不想让我 给你倒酒吗？
It's sad to drink alone.
一个人喝酒很伤心。
I'll drink with you.
我和你一起喝酒。
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I came to see if you are enjoying it
我是来看看你是否喜欢
enjoying the extravagant life of alcoholic beverage
享受酒的奢侈生活
and beautiful ladies.
和美丽的女士们。
It's not extravagant.
这并不奢侈。
But now I have
但现在我有
a beautiful lady by my side.
我身边有一位美丽的女士。
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
Are you well?
你好吗？
No.
不。
My mom
我的妈妈
died during my birth.
在我出生时就死了。
Since
自从
I came to this world,
我来到这个世界，
I never had a chance to
我从来没有机会
to be filial to her.
孝顺她。
She comes from a humble background.
她出身卑微。
She was like a weed
她就像一棵野草
It looked like a weed.
它看起来像一棵杂草。
Nobody cares about her,
没有人关心她，
no one noticed.
没有人注意到。
Even many years after his death,
甚至在他去世多年后，
She doesn't even have a title.
她甚至没有头衔。
That day in court,
那天在法庭上，
even if it meant a decent title, even if it meant
即使这意味着 一个体面的头衔，即使这意味着
I would lose my title of Lord Qin.
我就会失去秦王的称号。
Even if...
即使...
Even if the title is just one.
即使标题只有一个。
But they didn't give it to her
但他们没有给她
an empty title.
一个空标题。
My father
我的父亲
I didn't want to give him anything.
我不想给他任何东西。
In the past I knew
过去我知道
My father didn't like me.
我父亲不喜欢我。
And he blamed me for my mother's death.
他把我母亲的死归咎于我。
I thought that
我以为
In fact, he was a little
其实他有点
from my mother.
来自我母亲。
But now I discovered that
但现在我发现
He does not care
他不在乎
my mother's death.
我母亲的死。
He despises her origins.
他鄙视她的出身。
She has no relationship with him.
她和他没有任何关系。
Say.
说。
My mother's death
我母亲的去世
giving birth to me?
生下我？
She also suffered a lot
她也受了很多苦
for me too.
对我来说也是如此。
According to others,
据其他人说，
she took so many medicines
她吃了很多药
to accumulate waste can be piled up.
垃圾 可以堆积起来。
But when my mother was still alive
但当我母亲还活着的时候
always told me
总是告诉我
in this life,
此生，
did in this life
这辈子做过的
was giving birth to me.
正在生下我。
Shiqi,
Shiqi,
It's the saying about for a month,
俗话说 一个月
It's an absurd.
这是荒谬的。
By stupid people.
由愚蠢的人。
Your mother
你的母亲
to save you.
为了拯救你。
She doesn't want to see you
她不想见你
Seeing you blaming yourself like that.
看到你这样自责。
She would like you to live
她希望你活着
you can live a free life.
你可以过自由的生活。
Freedom.
自由。
It's freer.
更自由了。
There is no such thing as a free and easy life.
没有所谓的 自由自在的生活。
At first I thought that
起初我以为
after recovering Xichang,
收复西昌后
I could get out of this war.
我可以摆脱这场战争。
But now,
但现在，
everyone is plotting
每个人都在密谋
people are conspiring
人们在密谋
em Xichang.
em Xichang.
And even
乃至
even in Lord Qin's Mansion.
哪怕是秦王府里。
And me?
和我？
I can't do anything so small.
这么小的事情我都做不了。
I can't even
我什至不能
find a title
找一个标题
for my mother.
为了我妈。
I don't know either
我也不知道
what else can I do.
我还可以做些什么。
I feel that
我觉得
so useless.
太没用了。
I feel like crap.
我觉得自己很糟糕。
In fact, I'm very sad.
其实我很伤心。
I am very sad.
我很难过。
I know.
我知道。
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
In truth,
事实上，
I'm very envious of General Cui.
我很羡慕崔将军。
Because?
因为？
Because he can always be with you.
因为他可以一直陪在你身边。
I'm here now, right?
我现在就在这里，对吗？
But you have to leave.
但你必须离开。
Ok.
好的。
I promise you
我答应你
I won't leave.
我不会离开。
I won't go tonight.
今晚我不会去。
Serious?
严肃的？
Sim.
西姆。
Taozi.
Taozi.
You haven't seen me in so long,
你已经很久没见到我了
because you
因为你
To run away?
跑掉？
Because I...
因为我...
Because I went to get this for you.
因为我去给你拿这个。
What's that?
那是什么？
(Astragalus spp.) These are the medicinal herbs I have prepared for you.
（黄芪） 这些是我给你准备的药材。
Look,
看，
This is astragalus,
这是黄芪，
angelica,
当归,
this is a Chinese peony.
这是中国牡丹。
And these
还有这些
I bought some medicinal herbs
我买了一些药材
I bought it at the pharmacy,
我是在药店买的
and my dry parts
和我的干燥部分
to the mountains,
到山上，
in the mountains.
在群山中。
In truth,
事实上，
whenever I think of you,
每当我想起你时
I will collect herbs.
我会采集草药。
Whenever you miss me?
什么时候你想念我？
Look.
看。
You thought of me.
你想到了我。
One, two, four, six...
一、二、四、六……
You've thought of me more than 30 times.
你已经想我 30多次了。
Then,
然后，
if you miss me next time,
如果下次你还想我的话
You can come see me.
你可以来看我。
You can also write to me
你也可以写信给我
like Lord Qin
像秦王爷一样
and Lieutenant He like it.
何中尉很喜欢。
Serious?
严肃的？
Clear.
清除。
So, Tao Zi,
那么，桃子，
you missed me
你想我
all this time?
一直以来？
Guess.
猜测。
Have you guessed yet?
你猜到了吗？
How can you be so sure?
你怎么能这么肯定？
Because if you hadn't missed me,
因为如果你没有想念我
wouldn't have asked me to
不会要求我这样做
to see you see,
看到你看到，
you wouldn't have asked me to write letters
你不会让我 写信的
senhor shiqi.
senhor shiqi.
Right?
正确的？
I knew.
我知道。
You can say yes.
你可以说是的。
♪ A predestined relationship ♪
♪ 有缘份 ♪
♪ But roles that shouldn't always be ♪
♪ 但不应该总是这样的角色 ♪
♪ Unlimited Patience ♪
♪ 无限的耐心 ♪
♪ Wishing to escape this conflict ♪
♪ 希望逃离这场冲突 ♪
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
This afternoon.
今天下午。
I'm leaving.
我走了。
♪ To cut resentment and hatred ♪
♪ 消除怨恨和仇恨 ♪
Do not go.
不要去。
♪ The colorful array in the sky ♪
♪ 天空中五彩斑斓的阵列 ♪
♪ It belongs to just you and me ♪
♪ 它只属于你和我 ♪
Shiqi.
Shiqi.
If you move to another city,
如果你搬到另一个城市，
I Will Leave You.
我会离开你。
If Your Highness wishes,
如果殿下愿意的话
the whole world
整个世界
it will be yours.
它将是你的。
Why trade me for this?
为什么用我来交换这个？
I don't want this world.
我不想要这个世界。
I just want you.
我只是要你。
You may not desire the world,
你可能不渴望这个世界，
but those who want,
但那些想要的人，
They won't let you go easily.
他们不会轻易放你走的。
So let them have the world.
所以让他们拥有这个世界。
You are the only person
你是唯一的人
that I want.
我想要的。
♪ I'm willing to leave this world ♪ I want to leave this world for you ♪
♪ 我愿意离开这个世界 ♪ 我想为了你离开这个世界 ♪
♪ I have no regrets in this life ♪
♪ 此生无悔 ♪
♪ No matter the distance ♪
♪ 无论距离有多远 ♪
♪ I hear your echoes ♪
♪ 我听到你的回声 ♪
♪ The moment our shoulders ♪ ♪ when we cross ♪
♪ 我们肩膀的那一刻 ♪ ♪ 当我们交叉时 ♪
♪ It looks like the meteor shower ♪ (Lyrics) It stopped in the air
♪ 看起来像流星雨 ♪ （歌词） 它停在空中
♪ A family homecoming ♪
♪ 一家人回家 ♪
♪ And return the memory of our love ♪
♪ 还我们爱的记忆 ♪
♪ How can I forget? ♪
♪ 我怎么能忘记呢？♪
♪ You're in every scene ♪
♪ 每个场景都有你 ♪
♪ You are the sunrise the next day ♪ ♪ My heart beats hard ♪
♪ 你是第二天的日出 ♪ ♪ 我的心跳得厉害 ♪
♪ You are the final answer ♪ No regrets, no worries ♪
♪ 你就是最终的答案 ♪ 不后悔，不担心 ♪
♪ My unspoken words ♪ It's written on parchment ♪
♪ 我未说出口的话语 ♪ 它写在羊皮纸上 ♪
♪ Imitators who follow one after the other ♪
♪ 纷纷效仿的模仿者 ♪
♪ I can only count on you ♪ ♪ secretly my heart ♪
♪ 我只能依靠你 ♪ ♪ 暗暗地我的心 ♪
♪ You are forever missed ♪ ♪ Forever ♪
♪ 永远怀念你 ♪ ♪ 永远 ♪
♪ I'm willing to ♪ I want to leave this world for you ♪
♪ 我愿意 ♪ 我想为你离开这个世界 ♪
♪ I won't regret this life ♪
♪ 这辈子我不会后悔 ♪
(Lord Qin's House)
（秦王爷府）
♪ Let us never separate. ♪
♪ 让我们永不分离。♪
Heaven and earth can testify to our love. Witness our love.
天地可以见证我们的爱情。 见证我们的爱情。
Senhor shiqi.
Senhor shiqi.
Finally woke up.
终于醒了。
What time is it?
现在是几奌？
It's already noon.
已经是中午了。
I remember...
我记得...
I remember last night in the pavilion last night,
记得昨晚 在亭子里，
I got drunk.
我喝醉了。
I had a beautiful dream.
我做了一个美丽的梦。
What dream?
什么梦？
A dream
一个梦
a very happy dream.
一个非常幸福的梦。
It looks so real.
看起来很真实。
Did you dream about Lieutenant He?
你梦见过何中尉吗？
But she couldn't have come.
但她不可能来。
Looks like you got it
看起来你明白了
a serious case
情节严重
of love sickness.
的相思病。
Last night
昨夜
drinking alone.
一个人喝酒。
I wanted to drink with you,
我想和你一起喝酒
but you kicked me out.
但你把我赶了出去。
Sim.
西姆。
Mr. He, comma.
何先生，逗号。
You can eat.
你可以吃。
I can not eat.
我不能吃。
It's understandable.
这是可以理解的。
You stayed up all night.
你彻夜未眠。
Let's find a hotel
我们找个酒店吧
a hotel in the village ahead,
前面村庄里的一家旅馆，
let's rest for half a day
我们休息半天吧
for us to continue?
让我们继续？
There is no necessity.
没有必要。
i sleep
我睡觉
I slept a little.
我睡了一会儿。
Did you travel
你旅行了吗
a long trip.
一次长途旅行。
Traveling day and night,
日日夜夜的奔波，
to see Lord Qin,
去见秦王，
Why didn't you stay a little longer?
你为什么不再多呆一会儿呢？
Do you think that
你认为
just a little
只是一点点
to chat a little?
聊一会儿？
Just see it,
就看看吧，
I will be at ease.
我就会安心。
If discovered by someone else,
万一被别人发现了
there will be many complications.
会有很多并发症。
I just do not know
我只是不知道
how long will it take
它需要多长时间
your sadness and guilt
你的悲伤和愧疚
your sadness and guilt?
你的悲伤和愧疚？
Anyway, I still think
无论如何，我仍然认为
two lovers must always be
两个相爱的人必须永远在一起
forever.
永远。
It is not enough
那还不够
it is not enough.
那还不够。
I think someone
我认为有人
want to keep her ear
想留住她的耳朵
For a long time.
许久。
Mr He,
何先生，
like this?
像这样？
I just stayed away from him for a while
我只是离开他一段时间
and I miss him already.
我已经想念他了。
And you,
你呢，
Do you miss Lord Qin?
你想念秦王爷吗？
Sim,
西姆，
not see each other for a day,
一日不见，
it's been months.
已经好几个月了。
Right.
正确的。
(Shiqi)
(Shiqi)
(Shiqi.)
(Shiqi.)
(Wollong)
(卧龙)
Where have you been?
你去哪儿了？
Taozi was here yesterday.
桃子昨天来过。
She said she wanted dried fruit, so I bought it this morning.
她说她想要干果， 所以我今天早上就买了。
I was looking for someone to give it to her.
我一直在找人 给她。
Taozi came yesterday?
桃子昨天来了？
Sim,
西姆，
she came with Lieutenant He.
她是和何中尉一起来的。
I don't know
我不知道
where did she go
她去哪儿了
What if she stops to eat?
如果她停下来吃饭怎么办？
♪ Between the moon and your vows ♪
♪ 在月亮和你的誓言之间 ♪
♪ To fall into my heart ♪
♪ 坠入我的心 ♪
When did they leave?
他们什么时候离开的？
He left before dawn.
天亮之前他就离开了。
He said it would be bad if the imperial guardians saw them,
他说要是被禁卫军看见就不好了，
so they climbed the wall and came out before dawn.
于是他们爬上墙 ，天亮之前就出来了。
I have to see her.
我必须见她。
I have a lot to say to her.
我有很多话要对她说。
Senhor shiqi,
Senhor shiqi,
but His Majesty ordered to keep an eye out.
但陛下却下令 严密监视。
Isn't that disobeying orders?
这不是违抗命令吗？
And?
和？
Even if heaven comes, I want to see her.
就算天堂来了， 我也想见到她。
♪ You took me ♪ Through the night.
♪ 你带着我 ♪ 度过了整个夜晚。
♪ The shattered world brings with it ♪
♪ 破碎的世界随之而来 ♪
♪ You gave me a firm conviction ♪
♪ 你给了我坚定的信念 ♪
(Lyrics) In adversity ♪ The only light is eternal love ♪
（歌词）逆境中 ♪唯一的光明是永恒的爱♪
♪ Every breakup I endured ♪
♪ 我忍受的每一次分手 ♪
♪ Every minute, every second ♪ Looking for you at night ♪
♪ 每一分钟，每一秒 ♪ 夜里寻找你 ♪
(Tea)
（茶）
Welcome.
欢迎。
Please have a seat.
请坐。
I would like to try
我想试一试
our new tea?
我们的新茶？
Refreshing and refreshing.
清爽又清爽。
Let's eat this and eat.
我们把这个吃完再吃吧。
He is well.
他很好。
Mr He,
何先生，
we must reach Luoyang
我们必须到达洛阳
before dark.
天黑之前。
This place is very interesting.
这个地方很有趣。
Do you give the flowers with tea?
你送花时会配茶吗？
Enjoy.
享受。
Lieutenant He, experiment.
何中尉，实验。
It smells so good.
闻起来真香。
Why did you add another cup of tea?
你为什么又加一杯茶？
Haven't you left yet?
你还没走吗？
I will disappear.
我会消失。
Why are you here?
你为什么在这？
I came to see you.
我是来看你的。
Didn't you see enough last night?
昨晚你还没看够吗？
I was very drunk
我喝得很醉
I couldn't see it clearly.
我看不清楚。
Your journey was long.
你的旅程很漫长。
And you came here to see me.
而你来这里是为了见我。
I appreciate that.
我很感激。
I'm happy to do that.
我很高兴这样做。
I don't think it's a difficult task.
我不认为这是一项艰巨的任务。
Soon too
也很快
look for you.
找你。
You are not afraid that
你不怕
not afraid of being misunderstood
不怕被误解
I thought you would come with soldiers
我以为你会带着士兵来
to claim Luoyang.
夺取洛阳。
My father always wanted
我父亲一直想要
fight with Lord Qin
与秦王作战
on the battlefield.
战场上。
Are you giving
你是否给予
the oportunity?
机会？
If he puts you as the vanguard,
如果他让你当先锋
Maybe I'll lose.
也许我会输。
be captured
被俘虏
be captured.
被俘虏。
You must be merciful to me.
你一定要对我仁慈。
Don't worry.
不用担心。
If you are really in danger,
如果你真的遇到危险，
I will come to help you.
我会来帮助你的。
He is well.
他很好。
I appreciate your promise.
我很感激你的承诺。
But Lord Qin is really
不过秦王爷确实是
It's really very brave.
真的是非常非常勇敢。
Please don't give me
请不要给我
This opportunity.
这次机会。
I accept your auspicious words.
我接受你的吉祥话。
Then,
然后，
you always owe me a favor,
你总是欠我一个人情
and you won't be able to reciprocate.
而你将无法回报。
Li Ni is retreating to advance.
李妮 以退为进。
He sent his father a letter to his father
他 给父亲写了一封信
wishing your biological mother
祝愿 你的亲生母亲
like a godess.
像女神一样。
But my father was kind enough to
但我父亲很仁慈
he gave it to his mother for his mother.
他把它送给了他的母亲， 作为他母亲的礼物。
Li Ni is not reflecting in seclusion.
李妮闭关不反思。
He is constantly planning
他不断地计划着
regain control of the Zhenxi army.
重新控制镇西军。
Jun,
君，
my father asked you to stay
我父亲要你留下来
to oversee his mother's wedding.
监督他母亲的婚礼。
So he can only name her
所以他只能给她起名字
for you.
为你。
He left General Pei Yuan
他离开了裴渊将军
take the troops to Changzhou.
率兵前往常州。
We have to be careful
我们必须小心
Li Ni's influence in Changzhou,
李妮在常州的影响力，
or even
甚至
take over the Zhenxi army.
接管镇西军。
Don't worry,
不用担心，
as the Commander-in-Chief,
作为总司令，
I won't let them have that chance.
我不会让他们有这个机会的。
This time for Changzhou, the situation was critical.
这次对于常州来说， 形势十分危急。
I ordered Pei Yuan
我点了培源
to lead 30% of the forces
率领30%的兵力
and food at the front.
和前面的食物。
He must think that
他一定认为
that there will be Reinforcements arriving.
将会有 援军抵达。
That's what he wants.
这就是他想要的。
Pei Yuan only follows Li Ni's orders,
裴媛只听从李妮的命令，
it's not like this?
不是这样的吗？
If we lose for too long,
如果我们输得太久，
verei se Li Ni
美丽的李妮
protect him.
保护他。
Governor,
州长，
You recently recovered from poisoning.
您 最近刚刚从中毒中恢复过来。
(Tong Pass) Go rest.
(通通) 去休息吧。
Li Ni
李妮
It's very cunning.
这是非常狡猾的。
I suspect he is trying to intercept
我怀疑他是想拦截
which I sent to Baiyue I sent to Baiyue, who I am looking for.
我发给了百越 我发给了我要找的百越。
Biandu News.
边都新闻.
Li Ni was dismissed
李妮被解雇
his rank of commander.
他的指挥官军衔。
And he asked to reflect in isolation.
他要求隔离反思。
The court may send Lord Xin and Lord Qi
朝廷可遣 辛公、齐公
as commanders
作为指挥官
to the south.
向南方。
The incompetence of a General for the three armies.
一个将军对于三军的无能。
Like Lord Liang,
和梁王一样，
you take Li Ni,
you take Li Ni,
arrested Li Ni,
逮捕李妮，
he cut off his own arm.
他砍掉了自己的手臂。
Mayor.
市长。
Governor, what did you send? To look for the emperor's grandson,
州长，你寄了什么？ 为了寻找皇帝的孙子，
said that
说
It looks like he's hiding
看来他是躲起来了
in a village near Xichang.
在西昌附近的一个村庄里。
Order to capture the royal great-grandson alive.
下令活捉 皇家曾孙。
The others will be executed without mercy.
其他人将被 毫不留情地处决。
Sim.
西姆。
It's a really good opportunity.
这真是一个很好的机会。
Destiny is here.
命运就在这里。
I will have good luck.
我会有好运的。
PEI Yuan
PEI Yuan
sent an urgent message
发送了紧急消息
saying that Baiyue has already crossed
话说百越 已经穿越了
rio Han
里奥汉
and goes straight to Changzhou.
直奔常州。
Therefore, he asked the court for the situation in Changzhou.
于是，他向法庭询问了 常州的情况。
To send reinforcements, ask for reinforcements.
要派遣援军， 请请求援军。
Pai,
拜县，
In my humble opinion,
在我的愚见，
the expedition to Baiyue
百越远征
para Baiyue.
para Baiyue.
Furthermore, with the long march
此外，随着长征
there is no food on the way.
路上没有食物。
They are only a few tens of thousands of people.
他们不过数万 人。
PEI Yuan, from a military family
裴媛，出身军人世家
and leading the army for many years,
并带领军队多年，
must be able to
必须能够
be able to solve.
能够解决。
A General Pei Yuan
A General Pei Yuan
asked the court for help.
向法院寻求帮助。
If the court does not do this,
如果法院不这样做，
the Pei family will be sad.
裴家会伤心的。
to,
到，
you are showing compassion as a woman.
作为一个女人，你表现出了同情心。
The Pei family, even if it is powerful,
裴家就算再强大，
They are still their father's subjects.
他们仍然是父亲的臣民。
If we appease them
如果我们安抚他们
and we meet your requirements,
我们满足您的要求，
What is my father's position?
我父亲的立场是什么？
But the Imperial Court
但朝廷
it only allocated 30% of military supplies to them.
只分配了 30%的军需物资给他们。
In fact, it's not much.
事实上，并不多。
Pai,
拜县，
in the past, when Li Ni led the Zhenxi army,
当年， 李尼率领镇西军时，
the court had no food.
法庭没有食物。
But even so, the Zhenxi army followed
但即便如此，镇西军也跟着
marched from Laolan Pass
从老兰关出发
to recover these two cities.
收复这两座城市。
Now that
现在
the Zhenxi army returned
镇西军归来
30% of supplies.
供应量的30%。
Call for reinforcements
呼叫增援
It's just a try
这只是一次尝试
to obtain benefit without contributing.
不付出而获取利益 。
These are unspoken practices
这些都是不言而喻的做法
during the army.
当兵期间。
Don't be fooled, father.
别被愚弄了，父亲。
You are the leader of the clan.
你是氏族的领袖。
How do you think
你怎么想
How do you think we should respond?
您认为我们应该如何应对？
In my humble opinion,
在我的愚见，
the court has to give an order.
法院必须下达命令。
Ordering Pei Yuan not to delay
命令裴渊不要拖延
not to delay and attack from Changzhou
不可迟延， 从常州进攻
to end
结束
the solar rebels leading the expedition against Baiyue.
太阳叛军率领 远征百越。
They have no idea and don't know what they are doing.
他们不知道 也不知道自己在做什么。
Where are the reinforcements that General Pei Yuan and the Zhenxi army promised?
裴渊将军和镇西军许诺的援军在哪里？
When it's time to march,
到了游行的时候，
he only had 30%
他只有30%
30% strength and food.
30%的力量和食物。
Now if there is no food
现在如果没有食物
no reinforcements,
没有援军，
they asked us to
他们要求我们
to leave Changzhou to face the enemies.
离开常州 迎敌。
This is not just sending our Zhenxi soldiers
这不只是派遣 我们的镇西兵
for their deaths?
为了他们的死？
Hand this over to the Taozi.
把这个交给桃子。
We are already in this state
我们已经处于这个状态了
Are you still writing to Lieutenant He?
你还给何中尉写信吗？
The court does not want to send reinforcements
朝廷不想派遣援军
to support Changzhou.
支持常州。
Instead, they want Pei Yuan to attack.
反而是想让裴渊 出手。
I can't leave the capital now.
我现在还不能离开首都。
The only solution now is to ask the Cui army for help
现在唯一的办法就是 向崔军求助
to help Changzhou.
助力常州。
I'm leaving now.
现在我要走了。
Sr. shiqi,
Sr. shiqi,
Do you want the Cui Army
你想要崔军吗
in Changzhou.
在常州。
That will work?
那可行？
I just said in the letter that
我刚才在信中说
I'm stuck in Changzhou.
我被困在常州了
She can't just abandon me, can she?
她总不能就这么抛弃我吧？
What are you looking at?
你在看什么？
I'm looking
我在看
the most handsome guy
最帅的男人
the most beautiful boy in the world.
世界上最漂亮的男孩。
When the situation demands it, you must be humble.
当情况需要时， 你必须保持谦虚。
A real man can adapt.
真正的男人能够适应。
I know this letter
我知道这封信
can save Changzhou,
可以拯救常州，
then you must be a man
那你一定是个男人
which has never been dominated by anyone. I was never able to.
从来没有被任何人主宰过。 我从来没能做到。
I dare not accept that compliment.
我不敢接受这样的夸奖。
Just looking at this,
光是看这个，
I don't think His Highness Lord Qin did the right thing.
我不认为秦王殿下 这样做是对的。
Why not?
为什么不？
He must know that
他一定知道
If you have time,
如果你有时间，
when you have time.
当你有时间。
However, he chooses to do
然而他选择做
through straw.
通过稻草。
What if everything you do
如果你所做的一切
What are you going to do in just two days?
短短两天你打算做什么？
He should have done
他应该做的
wooden.
木制的。
It's more resistant that way.
这样就更有抵抗力了。
Xie Chang 'er pensou no futuro.
Xie Chang 'er pensou no futuro.
He wouldn't have had the idea
他不会有这个主意
the idea of ​​doing it for you For you.
为你做这件事的想法为 你。
After all, it never breaks.
毕竟，它永远不会破裂。
Seeing things this way,
这样看事情，
Mr. Qin really
秦先生真的
wasn't that attentive.
没那么专心。
Lieutenant He!
何中尉！
If you talk about the devil,
如果说起恶魔的话
he must appear.
他必须出现。
An urgent letter from Mr. shiqi.
世奇先生的一封紧急来信。
If Changzhou is in danger, no reinforcements.
若常州有危， 无援军。
I can only ask you to stop this situation.
我只能请求你停止 这种情况。
Your Majesty!
陛下！
Monarch.
君主。
Urgent report from Changzhou!
常州紧急报告！
What is the situation?
现在是什么状况？
General Pei Yuan attacked.
裴渊将军进攻。
But they fought for two days.
但他们打了两天。
They were outnumbered and surrounded by solar rebels.
他们寡不敌众 ，并被太阳叛军包围。
The Zhenxi army was almost wiped out.
镇西军几乎全军覆没。
And General Pei Yuan was seriously injured.
而裴渊将军也 受了重伤。
What about the city of Changzhou?
常州这个城市怎么样？
O General Pingliang Cui Yi
O General Pingliang Cui Yi
arrived with the Cui Army
随崔军抵达
to successfully eliminate it successfully .
就成功地消灭了它 。
General Pei Yuan seized the opportunity
裴渊将军抓住机会
to lead the Zhenxi army to cross the river
率镇西军 渡江
we set up a military camp in Changzhou.
我们在常州设立了军营 。
But...
但...
Cui Yi and Cui's army
崔义与崔军
entered the city of Changzhou.
进入常州城。
What?
什么？
Has Cuyi already taken the city of Changzhou?
粗衣已经攻下常州城了吗？
Pai,
拜县，
Changzhou city is It is very important.
常州市是 非常重要的。
Be in the hands of Sun Jing
落在孙静手里
ou de Cui Yi,
ou de Cui Yi,
it will be very disadvantageous for us.
这对我们来说将是非常不利的。
Pai,
拜县，
Pei Yuan lost the city of Changzhou
裴渊失常州城
his crime for his crime.
他的罪行 为他的罪行。
Brother,
兄弟，
Now is not the time to discuss crime and punishment.
现在不是 讨论罪与罚的时候。
Changzhou was lost under Pei Yuan's command.
常州在裴瑗指挥下失陷。
Why can't we hold him accountable?
为什么我们不能追究他的责任？
The father rejected it. The request for reinforcements
父亲拒绝了。 请求增援
call for reinforcements.
呼叫增援。
The great general Peixian personally came to the palace.
大将军沛县亲自 来到皇宫。
And asked his father to send reinforcements
并请求父亲 派援军
for the Zhenxi army.
为镇西军。
But, Jun, you said
但是，君，你说
General Pei Yuan is afraid to fight
裴渊将军不敢出战
and wanted to avoid it.
并想避免它。
Afterwards, three imperial decrees for Changzhou,
其后又下三旨 常州，
forcing him to fight.
逼迫他去战斗。
Now Changzhou is lost.
现在常州已经失守了。
We blame General Pei Yuan
我们责怪裴原将军
to General Pei Yuan,
致裴远将军，
afraid
害怕的
the Pei family will not tolerate it.
裴家不会容忍的。
Do something!
做一点事！
Cuyi!
Cuyi!
Last time he caught Dongdu,
上次抓东渡的时候，
has now taken Changzhou.
现已攻占常州。
If it continues like this,
如果再这样下去的话
What's the point of me being the Emperor?
我当皇帝有什么意义？
How can I face this world?
我该如何面对这个世界？
Pai,
拜县，
there is someone I would like to recommend.
我想推荐一个人。
If this person
如果这个人
lead the army,
带领军队，
they will definitely be able to capture Changzhou.
他们一定能攻下常州。
Who?
WHO？
Li Ni.
李妮.
No way.
决不。
Li Ni received an order to keep an eye out.
李妮接到命令，要 注意。
How can he lead soldiers?
他怎么能带兵呢？
Since I was a child, since I was a child.
从小到大， 从小到大。
Since I was a child.
从我小时候开始。
And the Cui Army never lost a battle.
而崔军 从来没有输过一场仗。
Furthermore, he is the only one
而且，他还是唯一一个
who always had a close relationship
谁总是有着密切的关系
with the Pei family.
和裴家。
If we let Ni
如果我们让妮
para Changzhou,
para Changzhou,
maybe he can dispel the chaos in the Pei family
或许他能平息 裴家的乱局
to revive the army.
以复兴军队。
Li Ni is arrogant and reckless.
李妮性格傲慢，鲁莽。
Does yours
你的吗
shouldn't it be considered?
难道不应该考虑吗？
In that case,
在这种情况下，
in this situation?
在这个情况下？
Will you yourself
你自己会吗
To the expedition?
去探险？
You are your father's eldest son.
你是你父亲的长子。
Even if my father agrees,
就算父亲同意了
the court and the ministers
法院和大臣
will not allow
不会允许
of being exported to such perigo.
被出口到这样的perigo。
Ok.
好的。
Lai is right.
莱是对的。
Issue a decree.
颁布法令。
Mister Qin reflected on his actions.
秦先生反省自己的行为。
Your punishment will be lifted.
对你的惩罚将被解除。
He will lead the troops to help Changzhou.
乃将率兵 援常州。
Sim.
西姆。
♪ If I forget the passage of time ♪
♪ 如果我忘记了时间的流逝 ♪
♪ Waiting for memory ♪
♪ 等待记忆 ♪
♪ To break the silence of the night ♪
♪ 打破夜晚的宁静 ♪
♪ The emotional scars in your heart ♪
♪ 你心中的情感伤痕 ♪
♪ They are the intertwining ♪
♪ 他们是交织在一起的 ♪
♪ I find it hard to let go ♪
♪ 我发现很难放手 ♪
♪ If the longing is not forgotten ♪
♪ 如果没有忘记渴望 ♪
♪ I want to go back ♪ I want to go back to the first moment ♪
♪ 我想回去 ♪ 我想回到最初的时刻 ♪
♪ The love we had today ♪ ♪ In our fateful situation ♪
♪ 我们今天拥有的爱 ♪ ♪ 在我们命中注定的处境中 ♪
♪ How I wish I was with you ♪
♪ 我多么希望能和你在一起 ♪
♪ If love still remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promises we made ♪
♪ 我们许下的承诺 ♪
♪ Even if this love hurts me ♪
♪ 即使这份爱让我受伤 ♪
♪ I will continue living for you ♪
♪ 我会继续为你而活 ♪
♪ I'm clinging to the memory ♪
♪ 我紧紧抓住记忆 ♪
♪ Waiting is my persistence ♪
♪ 等待是我的坚持 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ It doesn't matter if fate shakes everything, it can't take down what I have in my hands ♪
♪ 就算命运撼动一切也没关系，它也无法夺走我手中的东西 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I'm willing to sacrifice myself for you ♪
♪ 我愿意为你牺牲自己 ♪
♪ Waiting for your reply ♪
♪ 等待您的回复 ♪
♪ If love remembers ♪
♪ 如果爱还记得 ♪
♪ The promise I made to you ♪
♪ 我对你的承诺 ♪
♪ It doesn't matter if fate shakes everything, it can't take down what I have in my hands ♪
♪ 就算命运撼动一切也没关系，它也无法夺走我手中的东西 ♪
♪ I don't regret loving you ♪
♪ 我不后悔爱你 ♪
♪ I'm willing to sacrifice myself for you ♪
♪ 我愿意为你牺牲自己 ♪
♪ While I wait for your answer ♪
♪ 当我等待你的答复时 ♪